Michael Plunkett

Front-End Development UI/UX

(he/him)

- mrplunkett.com
- github.com/mister-blanket

about

I have spent my adult life marrying my passion for helping people with a deep undertanding of technology. I have taught children with Autism to compose electronic music, I have helped medical students adapt to new learning environments and I have played a part in transforming the Sally Beauty E-Commerce platform into an accessible, intuitive experience.

portfolio

blood lines is a 3D family tree visualizer built with React & D3

soil is a travel map, made with ES6 & Google Maps API

see more

skills

JavaScript (ES6) | React | Node | NPM | Webpack | Git | HTML | CSS | Sass | Salesforce | Photoshop | XD | Figma

education

B.M., Music Therapy

Arizona State University

work experience

Sally Beauty

2020 - present Denton, Texas

Sr. Front End Developer

Innovated strategies to improve site performance and reduce build time.

Worked with partners to implement experiments, which reduced bounce rate and increased conversion and RPV.

In addition to fostering the development of two employees under my care I was a leadership mentor to another ecommerce team member.

Mr. Plunkett

2018 - present Dallas, Texas

Front End Developer

Developed and launched an international multi-lingual ecommerce platform.

Produced business sites for clients with a focus on mobile first, SEO, accessibility and clean UI design.

St. George's University of London

2015 - 2017 London, U.K.

IT Support Analyst

Worked with SQL and Dev team in database debugging.

Wrote Visual Basic for Applications (VBA) code to improve auditing workflow & documentation.

Gateway Academy

2006 - 2014 Scottsdale, AZ

Director of Music

Improved student computer literacy through creating and leading a digital music program.

Led the curriculum development team in developing new teaching plans.